Alejandro Sabogal

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack developer proficient in JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby and Ruby on Rails. A quick learner and creative problem solver with a passion for learning, he has experience in several industries including Banking and Finance, Hospitality, and Audio Engineering, complemented with strong familiarity in Entrepreneurship and Business Development.

| asabogal.dev@gmail.com | |
|------------------------|--|
| 954- 261-1961 | |

<u>alejandro-sabogal.com</u>

linkedin.com/in/alejandro-sabogal-dev

github.com/asabogal

medium.com/@asabogal

EXPERIENCE

REACT + RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - Kon-Tiki Web App (in progress)
GitHub Repo

- Tools: React.js, Ruby on Rails, CSS, In-Line Styling, FontAwesome, Material UI
- Freelance work for Kon-Tiki Bar
- Restaurant Web App with React.js frontend design and custom table reservation system and user database on Rails backend

REACT DEVELOPER - PORTFOLIO SITE

GitHub Repo

- Tools: React.js, Radium, CSS, In-Line Styling
- Personal Portfolio built from scratch, utilizing multiple frontend design techniques
- Client side rendering and server side deployed

REACT + REDUX + RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - INTERVAL-TRAINING-TIMER GitHub Repo | Video Demo

- Tools: React.js, Redux, Ruby on Rails, CSS, reactstrap
- Customizable High Intensity Interval Training Timer App
- React.js frontend client and Rails API backend
- Fully functional and deployed on Heroku

JAVASCRIPT + RUBY ON RAILS (API) DEVELOPER - UEFA-SCHEDULES GitHub Repo | Video Demo

- Tools: JavaScript, Ruby on Rails API, External API, Postman, JQuery, Bootstrap
- Web App fetching European soccer league data from external API, serialized through Rails API, and rendered to users via JavaScript/AJAX
- Fully functional and deployed on Heroku

RUBY ON RAILS DEVELOPER - RECORDBOX-REVIEWS

GitHub Repo | Video Demo

- Tools: Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bcrypt, OmniAuth, Google Cloud Platform
- Full CRUD application with MVC design
- User authentication with Bcrypt Gem and OmniAuth with Facebook
- Fully functional and deployed on Heroku with Google Cloud data store

TECHNICAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

Full Stack Software/Web Development

Obejct Oriented Programming

Flatiron School

New York, NY - 04/2018 - 01/2019

Audio Technology/Engineering

SAE Institute of Technology

Miami, FL

Finance and Business Administration

Florida International University

Miami, FL

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Spanish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

BUSINESS CONSULTANT - CR Properties/Gallery Hotels LLC | New York, NY | August 2016 - Present

- Business Consultant for the company's Real Estate Properties and Hotel & Restaurant operations.
- Developed and actualized new business strategies and logistics leading to a 73% increase in revenues from previous year.

AUDIO MIXER/SOUND ENGINEER - The Kitchen Studios | Miami, FL | January 2011 - February 2016

- Audio processing and rendering on digital and analogue consoles.
- Troubleshoot and maintained digital audio workstations.

CO-FOUNDER/OWNER - PLOT Bookings | Miami, FL | December 2007 - December 2014

- Co-founder of a top music event production series and promotion outfits in the United States.
- Responsible for Management, Finance, A&R, Marketing/Social Media, and live sound coordination.

PRIVATE BANKER - Bank of America Private Bank/Banc of America Investments | Miami, FL | January 2007 - December 2008

- Assistant to the National Sales Manager of the International Wealth Management Group and head of the Miami's International Private Bank office.
- Worked directly with high net-worth clients by providing front office service and executing day-to-day transactions and investment assistance